（ヤサコ）ヌルたちによると
彼らは苦しみの種を食べるうちに
According to the Nulls, by eating the seed of pain,
苦しみを求める生き物としての命を
得たそうです
they became creatures whose goal is pain itself.
（イサコ）お前 なぜ暗号炉が…
You!
Why do you have an encode reactor?
（ヤサコ）わ… 分からないわ
I don't know!
さっきのメタタグを
貼ったからかしら？
Probably because I just put that metatag on?
それだけでは
暗号炉ができるわけ…
Just doing that shouldn't make an encode reactor...
まさか！
It can't be!
あのときのキラバグが？
The kirabug from back then...
Anyway, let's move on.
とにかく急ぎましょう
The granted wish
（イサコ）暗号炉が
自然発生するなんて…
The encode reactor couldn't have activated on its own.
ねえ
どういうことなの？
What do you mean?
さっきは すまなかった
Sorry about before.
もっと ちゃんと説明してやれば
お前もこんなことはしなかっただろ
If I'd explained better,
you wouldn't have done that.
黒客(ヘイクー)に与えた暗号は
The encode I gave to the Hackers Club
イマーゴがなくても使えるように
改造した擬似的なものだ
is a fake that can be used without possessing the Imago.
駅向こうも 恐らく同じだろう
The guys from the other side of the station probably use a similar one.
だが お前のは違う
But yours is different.
Yours is directly linked to the Imago.
イマーゴと直結してる
今のお前の状態は
恐らく私と同じだ
Your actual condition
is similar to mine.
暗号炉はイマーゴと直結して
The encode reactor is connected to the Imago
思考から
直接 暗号を取り出す構造体だ
and is now structured to react to your thoughts directly.
しかし イマーゴと直結した
暗号炉を―
But if the encode reactor is connected to the Imago
あの新型のレベル３フォーマットで
攻撃されたら
and is attacked by that new type of level-three format,
無事では済まない
it won't end without causing injury.
特に 私のように
深く直結している場合は
Especially in a case like mine, where the connection is deep inside.
おまけに この古流の暗号
Moreover, this old-type encode acts by consuming the Imago.
イマーゴを消費して
暗号を出している
危険すぎる
（ヤサコ）そんな…
It's too dangerous.
But that's...
お前の暗号炉はまだ浅い
これ以上いじるな
Your encode reactor is still thin.
Do not stimulate it anymore.
Okay.
クソ！
Crap!
おわっ…
神社にも入ってくるんじゃ
どこに逃げればいいんだよ！
They can also enter shrines!
Where the heck should I hide?!
（オバちゃん）
個人の家なら すぐには入れない
They can't go into private houses!
どこでもいいから
民家に逃げ込むのよ
Just go into a house, it doesn't matter which!
民家って 他人の家かよ？
そんなことできるか！
A house?!
How can I just drop in at someone's house?!
ひ… ひえ～！
どわっ…
ハァ ハァ…
（男性）
こらっ！　人んちで何やっとる！
Hey you!
ひぃ… ひええ～！
What the hell are you doing in my house?!
Sorry!
ごめんなさ～い！
他人の家に簡単に入れるかよ！
Do you think it's easy to drop in at someone's house?
そうねえ… 分かった！
Indeed...
Oh, right!
“ションベン チビりそう”って
言えば入れるぞ
Say you've gotta take a pee, and they'll let you in!
Impossible... There are so many!
（フミエ）まさか あれほどとは…
Fumie!
（ダイチ）フミエ～！
ショ ショ…
Pee...
Pee!
ショ？
Pee?
I gotta take a peeeeeeee!
ションベン チビリそうだああ～！
フミエ！
Fumie!
あっ オバちゃん
Aunty!
ダイチを見なかったか？
Did you see Daichi?
見たもなにも さっき
“ションベン チビッた”って
See, you say?!
He was running like crazy, shouting that he had to take a pee!
絶叫しながら走り去って行ったわよ
どっちへ行った？
Where did he go?
どっちへ行けばいいんだあ～？
Where should I go?!
Oh! So this kind of place is safe?
そ… そうか
こういう所も大丈夫なのか
なんだ 楽勝だぜ
Man, that was easy!
（アナウンス）ただ今から
メガマス特例 第３項を申請します
As of now, we are submitting a request to Megamass under Special Article Three.
Permission Granted
許可されました
Permission granted.
B-But that's no good at all!
ダ… ダメじゃん！
（イサコ）おい
（ダイチ）イ… イサコさん
Hey...
Miss Isako...
I mean, Isako!
あっ じゃない… イサコ！
Throw that capsule here!
カプセルをこっちに投げろ！
何？
Take this!
それ！
（ダイチ）ハァ…
Densuke! Thank goodness!
デンスケ… よかった
Are you all right?
無事か？
We're fine.
大丈夫よ　でも天沢(あまさわ)さんが…
But Amasawa is...
天沢さん 大丈夫？
Amasawa, are you all right?
Hey...
お… おい どうかしたのか？
大丈夫か？
What happened to you?
Can you stand?
I'm all right.
大丈夫だ
Ah! I forgot!
あっ 忘れてた！
（イサコ）な… なんだ？
What's that?
If I hand over that thing,
そ… そいつを渡してほしくば
大黒(だいこく)黒客を俺に返せ！
you have to give me back the Hackers Club!
You already handed it over...
もう渡しちゃってるわよ
Damn it...
あっ しまった
It's fine with me.
いいさ
終わったら 全部 返してやる
When all this is over, I'll give everything back to you.
Okonogi, you're the witness.
小此木(おこのぎ) お前が証人だ
Tell those two guys that they can go back to the original Hackers Club.
２人は元の黒客に戻れと言っておけ
Are you serious?
本当か？
If I'm lying, you can take my life.
ウソだったら
私の命をくれてやるさ
I don't need your life.
お前の命なんかいらねえ
I just want you to give me back the Hackers Club.
黒客さえ返してもらえば
それでいい
What's the plan now?
これからどうする？
We're gonna look for the Coil Space.
我々はコイルスの空間を探す
Aunty, take care of Kyoko.
オバちゃん 京子(きょうこ)をお願い
Got it.
分かった
Let's go!
行くぞ
（イサコ）あっ… クソ！
Crap!
In any case, what's this "path" thing?
（フミエ）
そもそも この道順ってなんなの？
The reason why you need to follow a path to enter obsolete Space
なぜ古い空間に入るのに
道順がいるのか
was hidden in the data that survived the attack at Okonogi's house.
焼け残った小此木家の資料に
その答えがあったわ
When Coil was sold,
コイルスは買収されたとき
they must've hidden data that they wanted to conceal from the public.
公にされたくない
実験試料を抱えていた
Probably relating to Imago or Illegals.
恐らく イマーゴや
イリーガルに関するね
So, those things sealed in twisty paths form obsolete Space, huh.
それらを迷い道で封印したものが
古い空間だったのじゃな
And the paths found by Yasako and Kanna are part of those.
ヤサコやカンナが
見つけた道がそれね
Exactly.
そうよ
Either I or the 2.0 smashed all the shallow areas.
浅い領域は全て
私か2.0が潰してしまった
If there are some left,
残ってるとすれば
深い道のりだけだ
they must be in a deeper layer.
I think it must be like a complicated labyrinth.
恐らく長い迷路のように
なっているだろう
Let's split up for now.
二手に分かれよう
That way, we have more chances.
（イサコ）
そのほうが確率は高くなる
If we find something, we'll get in contact by phone and join up.
見つけたら
連絡を取って合流しよう
Amasawa...
天沢さん 大丈夫？
Will you be all right?
Am I the one who you should be worried about now?
私は心配される側なのか？
After all, I have the Imago.
私にだってイマーゴはある
Right...
そうね
The format is about to end.
もうすぐフォーマットが終わる
After that, you're gonna search over there.
そうしたら お前はそっちを探せ
I'm gonna go the other way.
私はこっちだ
According to the data,
資料によるとイマーゴの発見は
偶然だったらしいわ
the discovery of the Imago was an accident.
The engineers at Coil discovered that
量子回路のある
特殊な基盤パターンが
a base pattern in a special quantum circuit functioned as a highly sensitive antenna
過去 例を見ないほど
高性能なアンテナになることに
unlike any seen before.
コイルスの主任技師が気づいた
Thanks to that circuit, even weak electromagnetic waves could carry data at high speed,
おかげで微弱な電磁波でも
高速通信できるようになり
giving rise to cyberglasses and a revolutionary information infrastructure.
今の電脳メガネと
革命的な通信インフラが実現した
Obviously, Coil tried to understand how the phenomenon worked,
当然 コイルスは その現象の理論を
解明しようとしたけど
but they failed to discover its true nature.
原理すら分からなかった
Nonetheless, reproducing the phenomenon and copying the circuit were easy.
しかし 現象の再現と
回路のコピーだけは簡単だった
Management plunged into production,
経営者は量産に踏み切り
コイルスは急成長した
and Coil grew rapidly.
But the engineers' discovery wasn't limited to just that.
でも 技師の発見は
それだけじゃなかった
They also discovered that the circuit could transmit something more than electromagnetic waves.
回路が電磁波以外の何かを
受信していたのを発見したのよ
Something more?
（フミエ）何かって？
Human consciousness.
（オバちゃん）人間の意識よ
The engineers called it Imago and conducted more experiments,
技師は それをイマーゴと名づけ
さらに実験を繰り返した
like extracting consciousness from the Space,
人間の意識を
電脳空間に取り出したり
or manipulating consciousness.
イマーゴを逆流させて
意識を操作したり
Then, they built a Coil System based on the Imago,
そしてイマーゴを中心とした
コイルシステムを構築し
and used it for cybercures.
電脳医療にも応用した
The place containing these cures
それらを隠した場所が
今もどこかに眠っているの
is still hidden somewhere.
Time's up.
時間じゃ
The compulsory format has ended.
（アナウンス）
一斉フォーマットは終了しました
Next, because we are carrying out ongoing adjustments,
引き続き
調整プロセスに入るため―
許可された方以外は
まだメガネの使用を控えてください
It'll be easier like this.
only authorized personnel should use their glasses.
（猫目(ねこめ)）これで少し
やりやすくなるな
許可された方以外は
まだメガネの使用を控えてください
Repeat.
Here!
The compulsory format has ended.
きた！　先生のパスワード
まだ生きてた
The professor's password still works!
Next, because we are carrying out ongoing adjustments,
only authorized personnel should use their glasses.
Indeed...
やはり そうか
今まで先生の首輪が―
The professor's collar sealed the functions till now.
機能を封印していたんだ
If I connect that Coil Node to the Coil Domain...
このコイルスノードを
コイルドメインで接続すれば―
Perhaps not as well as with kirabugs,
キラバグほどではないが
通路が開ける
but I can open the passage!
Now,
あとは贈り物を用意するだけだ
I just have to prepare something to send.
I can't hear any voices.
（ヤサコ）声が聞こえない
フォーマットのせいかしら？
Maybe it's because of the format?
Again...
まただ
Right...
そうだ あのときも
こんな階段のある神社だった
Back then too,
there was a shrine with stairs, like this one.
I want to live here like this, with you, forever!
（幼少のイサコ）このまま ずっと
ここで一緒に暮らしたい
That kid will break it!
あの子に壊されちゃう
I beg you!
お願い！　この世界を守って
Protect this world!
Finally I can contact you!
（猫目）
よかった やっとつながった
Nekome!
猫目
I kept calling you.
（猫目）ずっと電話していたんだ
連絡が遅れてすまなかった
Sorry for calling so late.
At this point, it's no use!
（イサコ）何を今さら…
お前が私を売ったんだろ！
You're the one who sold me out!
Not at all!
（猫目）違う！
Do you doubt me, after I spent five years looking for Nobuhiko with you?
５年間も一緒に信彦(のぶひこ)を捜してきた
僕を疑うのか？
Then explain to me, Sosuke.
（イサコ）説明して 宗助(そうすけ)
What happened to...
私のお兄ちゃんは 一体…
my brother...
Listen to me, Yuko.
（猫目）聞いてくれ 勇子(ゆうこ)
A certain group is trying to block us.
ある勢力が
僕らの邪魔をしようとしている
Don't believe their lies.
ヤツらの偽情報を信じるな
Nobuhiko...
信彦は… 今も生きている
is still alive.
What?
なんだって？
（猫目）信彦の身柄は
ヤツらが押さえている
Those people have Nobuhiko's body.
ヤツらはお前にウソを吹き込み
病室に細工をしたんだ
They brainwashed you with their lies, and they played a trick in the hospital room.
一体 ヤツらって誰なの？
But who are "they"?
（猫目）メガネの不具合が
公表されるのを恐れているヤツらだ
People who fear improper uses of the glasses.
だが 一番いい方法を見つけた
But I did find the best way.
全てを解決し
皆が幸せになる方法だ
A way that solves everything, and makes everyone happy.
幸せ？
Happy?
（猫目）ああ コイルドメインを
探しているんだろ？
Yeah.
You're looking for the Coil Domain, aren't you?
小此木優子(ゆうこ)の犬を助けるために
In order to save Okonogi's dog.
なぜ… それを？
How do you know...
（猫目）
僕は その道順を知っている
I know the path to it.
（イサコ）なんだって？
What?
（猫目）さっき突き止めたんだ
I just found it.
偶然 本社が隠していた
コイルスのデータを拾った
I just found some data on Coil that the head office was hiding.
それだけじゃない
あの犬はコイルスノードだ
And not only that.
That dog is a Coil Node.
コイルドメインで
あの犬を 直接 接続すれば
If we connect that dog directly to the Coil Domain,
我々の目的も果たせる
we can achieve our objective.
我々の？
Our?
（猫目）
あっちへの通路を開けるんだ
We can open the passage to "the other side."
浅い空間からだと―
From a shallow Space, we need a forceful method like kirabugs.
キラバグのような
強引な方法が必要になる
だが コイルドメインは
コイルスノードで接続すれば
But if we connect to the Coil Domain with a Coil Node,
すぐに開くことができるんだ
you can open it immediately.
信彦のいる あっちへの通路をな
Nobuhiko is also there.
In the passage to "the other side."
いいか？　必ず犬を
この場所まで連れて来るんだ
Got it?
You have to take the dog to this place.
ただし １人で
But you have to come alone.
（イサコ）どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?
（猫目）事情があるんだ
There are reasons.
これが信彦と会える
最後のチャンスだ
This is your last chance to meet Nobuhiko again.
（ヤサコ）天沢さん
Amasawa!
デンスケが…
Densuke is...
（ヤサコ）
それに道順も見つからないの
Moreover, I can't find the path.
道順が分かった
（ヤサコ）ホントに？
I found the path.
Really?
ああ　時間がない 急ぐぞ
Yeah.
There's no time. Hurry!
（イサコ）間違いない
There's no doubt!
空間の深度が
どんどん深くなっている
The depth of the Space is becoming greater and greater.
私も感じるわ
I can feel it, too!
（イサコ）ここは…
This is...
（ヤサコ）新校舎だわ
...the new school building.
全然 気づかなかった
まさか学校の下にあるなんて
I never noticed it before.
I can't believe it's under the school.
このビルには
メガマスも入っている
Megamass is also in this building.
（ヤサコ）守衛さん
（守衛）んっ？
Mr. Security Guard.
忘れ物をしちゃったんです
学校に行かせてください
We forgot something at school.
Please let us in.
（守衛）えっ？
（ヤサコ）ママに怒られちゃう
Mom will be mad at us.
ああ… しかたないな 特別だよ
It can't be helped...
Just this time then.
ちょっと待て 様子を見る
Wait up.
I'm gonna check the area.
何かいるの？
Is there something?
天沢さん？
Amasawa?
すまない
Sorry.
天沢さん 待って！
Amasawa!
Wait!
（イサコ）ここからは私一人で行く
I'm gonna go on alone from here.
なんで？　こんなことやめて！
Why?
Stop this already!
（イサコ）すまん
Sorry...
なんだと？
（メガばあ）どうしたのじゃ？
What?!
Whassup?
うん エレベーターの中…
Yeah... in the elevator.
（オバちゃん）
分かった アクセスしてみる
Got it.
I'll try to access it.
天沢さん 切らないで！
Amasawa! Don't hang up!
犬は必ず助ける 心配するな
I'll save the dog for sure.
Don't worry.
（ヤサコ）そうじゃない
どうして こんなことを…
It's not about that! Why are you doing this?
（イサコ）危険があるんだ
この先に 多分 ワナが待ってる
There's a danger.
I think there's a trap for me.
（イサコ）
しかし 犬を治せるデバイスを
見つけるには行くしかない
But in order to find the device that can heal the dog,
I have to go.
危険な目に遭うのは
私一人でいい
It's best if I'm the only one...
to face the danger.
（ヤサコ）そんな…
But...
（イサコ）
お前とは友達になれたのかどうか
よく分からない
I don't really understand if you and I have become friends.
私には友達というものが
よく分からないから
Because...
I don't really know the meaning of "friend."
でも こんなに近くまで
来てくれた他人は―
But you're the first one who...
お前が初めてだ
has gotten so close to me.
でも やはり…
But after all...
私が住む世界は進む道が違うんだ
the world I live in,
and the path I have to follow are different from yours.
天沢さん
Amasawa...
（イサコ）
人と人の間には距離がある
There's a distance between people.
遠い距離が…
A large distance.
私と兄さんの間にも…
Between my brother and me as well.
でも ゆっくりと丁寧に探せば―
But...
if I search patiently, slowly,
隔たりをつなぐ道が
見つかるかもしれない
I may be able to find a path that shortens this distance.
その道は すごく細くて
That path is extremely narrow,
ちょっと目をそらすと
すぐに見失ってしまう
so if I take my eyes off it for a second,
I'll lose it forever.
だから 必死に目を凝らして
探さなくちゃいけないんだ
So,
I have to keep my eyes fixed on it and search.
道があることを
信じられなくなったら
If I lose my faith in the existence of this path,
その道は 本当に
なくなってしまうかもしれない
it may disappear for real.
だから 必ず道はあると
信じ続けなくちゃならないんだ
That's why
I have to keep believing that this path exists.
すまない
I'm sorry.
（イサコ）今までの出来事は
多分 全て私が原因だ
I may be the cause of everything that happened till now.
この犬も 原川(はらかわ)も…
To this dog,
to Harakawa,
そして 多分 葦原(あしはら)カンナも…
and maybe...
to Kanna Ashihara.
天沢さん？
Amasawa...
All the things you see with the glasses...
メガネで見えるものなんて
全てまやかしだ
are nothing but fakery.
もうメガネなんて捨てろ
Throw your glasses away already.
そして 手で触れられるものだけを
信じるんだ
And
believe only in things you can touch with your hands.
さもないと 私のように…
Otherwise, just like me...
メガネに殺されるぞ
your glasses will kill you.
天沢さん 切らないで！
Amasawa, don't hang up!
さよなら
Goodbye.
Access complete
天沢さん！
Amasawa!
Coil Space?
コイルスの空間か？
このデバイスだ
This is the device!
（デンスケ）アウ～…
（イサコ）じっとしてろよ
Don't move.
すぐに終わる
It'll be over in no time.
こっちだわ
It's this way.
（イサコ）これは…
This...
あの鍵が
コイルスのデバイスだったのか
So this key
is a Coil device!
やはり この首輪が
修復を邪魔していたんだ
As I thought,
this collar was blocking the repairs.
よかった うまくいったんだな
Thank goodness!
It worked!
What is this?
なんだ これは？
これは まるでキラバグ…
This is exactly like...
the kirabugs!
（猫目）ああ そのとおりだ
Yes, exactly.
（イサコ）宗助！
Sosuke!
（猫目）
よかったな その犬 病気が治って
Thank goodness, that dog was cured.
勇子 我々は
全てを解決する方法を見つけたんだ
Yuko,
we found the way to solve everything.
（猫目）その犬の電脳体だ
Namely, the cyberbody of that dog.
このコイルドメインでは―
In this Coil Domain, it will become the fuel for the Coil Node instead of the kirabugs.
コイルスノードが
キラバグの代わりとして
燃料になるんだ
なんだって？
What?
待て やめろ！
Wait.
Stop!
（猫目）なぜ邪魔をするんだ！
Why are you hindering me?
もう これが信彦に会える
最後の方法なんだぞ
This is your very last chance to meet Nobuhiko.
どういう意味だ？
What do you mean?
Nobuhiko is already dead, after all.
（猫目）
信彦は やはり すでに死んでいる
肉体的にはな
At least, his body is.
ウソだ！
That's a lie!
（猫目）ウソじゃない
信彦は生きている あっちでな
It's not a lie.
Nobuhiko is alive on the other side.
（イサコ）何を… 何を言って…
What...
are you talking about?
（猫目）だから やっと
これで信彦に会えるんだ 勇子
So,
you can finally meet Nobuhiko, like this... Yuko.
（猫目）これでお前の望みもかなう
This way, your wish will come true.
あの人も喜んでいる
お前に会いたがっていたぞ
She'll be glad, too.
She wanted to meet you.
She?
あの人？
（猫目）ミチコさん
Miss Michiko.
宗助 お前は 一体 何を…
Sosuke...
What the hell...
did you do...
（猫目）ミチコさんと契約した
I made a pact with Miss Michiko.
宗助！
Sosuke!
（猫目）
君は あっちでお兄さんと暮らす
You'll be living on the other side with your brother.
僕は あっちの存在を実証できる
I'll be able to prove the existence of the other side.
これでみんな幸せになれる
君もうれしいだろ？　勇子
That way, everyone's happy.
You're happy, aren't you?
Yuko.
Do you remember now?
思い出したか？
ミチコさんは
お前と信彦を引き離したんじゃない
It wasn't Miss Michiko who separated you and your brother.
違う…
That's not true...
（猫目）願いをかなえたんだ
ずっと一緒にいられるように
She granted your wish.
So you could be with Nobuhiko forever,
信彦をあっちに閉じ込めてほしい
という―
he was sealed on the other side.
お前の願いをな
That was your wish.
やめろ！
Stop it!
（デンスケ）ワン…
（猫目）何をする！
What are you doing?!
これは…
This is...
デンスケ！
Densuke!
行け！
Go away!
（猫目）何をするんだ！
What the hell are you doing?
（イサコ）
これ以上 通路を広げたら
私の暗号炉を暴走させる
If you keep on enlarging the passage,
I'll make my encode reactor go berserk!
（猫目）何？
What?
その通路を閉じろ！
Close that passage!
（猫目）バカな…
そんなことをしたら お前は死ぬぞ
That's nonsense!
If you do that, you'll die!
かまわない
I don't care.
（猫目）信彦に会いたくないのか？
もうすぐ会えるんだぞ
Don't you want to meet Nobuhiko?
You can meet him soon!
あっ デンスケ！
Densuke!
天沢さん！
Amasawa!
来るな！
Don't come in!
天沢さん！
Amasawa!
やはり ワナだった
So it really was a trap!
お前の犬を救ってやれなかった
I wasn't able to save your dog.
（イサコ）すまない
全ては私が… 私が始まりなんだ
I'm sorry.
I was
the cause of everything.
I've remembered.
思い出した
もともと 私が願ったんだ
I was the one
who made the wish in the first place.
天沢さん？
Amasawa...
（イサコ）“お兄ちゃんを
あっちに連れてって”って
I said,
"Take my brother to the other side."
To Miss Michiko.
ミチコさんに…
I wished for a place where I could live
お兄ちゃんと一緒に永遠に
２人だけで暮らせる場所を願った
only with my brother forever!
そして…
兄は戻ってこられなくなった
My brother couldn't come back anymore.
But that's...
そんな…
Because I asked!
私が願ったんだ ミチコに
Asked Michiko!
逃げろ！
Run away!
ワン…
Densuke...
デンスケ…
Densuke!
デンスケー！
Damn it...
（猫目）クソ！　通路が不完全だ
The passage is incomplete!
This Space will be formatted.
（アナウンス）
このフロアをフォーマットします
Yasako!
（オバちゃん）ヤサコ 来い！
Come.
Densuke...
デンスケ…
あっ 天沢さんが…
Amasawa?
Yasako...
（オバちゃん）ヤサコ
Wait up!
ま… 待て！
Ama... sawa...
天沢さん…
NO!
イヤー！
Preview
Next time on Dennou Coil:
The kids cast their glasses away.
The Kids Cast Their
Glasses Away
See you next time!
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
〝メガネを捨てる
子供たち 〞
お楽しみに